Hey guys, quick one here, a bit of a dry subject,
but we're going to be talking about the quote principles that make up the
backbone of client professionalism here at Jamie Fitness.
But we've heard it before, but we really pride ourselves on our professionalism guys
and it really stands out. It stands out in every team we work at
and it's why we do so well. So let's get started.
Punctuality, okay, being on time is not optional.
It's a requirement. Each session to start and end exactly on the
minute, guys. Clients will notice if you're one to two minutes late or you
finish one to two minutes early. You want to make sure that as soon
as it ticks over to the next session, you're wrapping up and you start
the next one. Okay. I typically recommend to finish each session one minute
early, one minute early to press save.
Rate the workout, review the personal best and discuss the next steps or just
say hello. I mean, sorry. Goodbye. And prepare for your next client,
which doesn't take much time, which if you text one click of the calendar,
click the name, then you're off. That's awesome.
This shows respect for your clients. Time and it sets the standard for punctuality.
Before sessions, you have to aim to get to the gym five minutes early.
Okay. I love this quote. Being late,
no, sorry. Being early is on time.
Being on time is late and being late.
It is unforgivable. What this means is if you just woke up on time,
you still need time to prepare. So you really,
you're not on time, you're late. Next up,
communication. Communication should be conducted exclusively through JF Coach.
When you're first reaching out to a new client, flick them a text,
no worries, but ongoing only through the app.
This keeps all the interactions documented and ensures that we maintain a high-level professionalism.
It also helps you keep your work and personal life set for guys,
which is essential. For long-term success,
accommodating clients needs, flexibility is key.
Whether it's a minor adjustment to a workout plan or rescheduling a session,
your ability to adapt demonstrates your commitment to each client's unique
needs. However, always remember to maintain professional boundaries,
okay? Curse you in respect.
It's not just about being polite, it's about a cornerstone of professionalism.
Listen attentively to your clients and offer constructive and positive feedback,
and maintain a friendly, professional manner.
It's friendly, yet professional demeanor at all times.
Confidentiality, but shared in the training session stays in the training session.
Client information, whether it's about the fitness level,
history, or personal life, is confidential,
so treat it as such. Follow up.
Up to every few sessions, it's good to practice sending a follow up message
in the app. It's nice. It takes no time at all,
but it makes a world of a difference. This could be a recap of
the session, their personal best, or a simple word of encouragement.
It contributes significantly to the client's overall experience.
Lastly is encouragement. Never underestimate the power of positive enforcement.
Whether it's celebrating a new PB or acknowledging a consistent effort,
your encouragement can be the fuel that drives client motivation.
Look, by adhering to these principles, you're not just doing a job.
You're changing a client's life and elevating the experience with us.
This is what sets us apart, and it's what's going to set you apart
as a trainer.